Guide to the McCann-Erickson Audiovisual Collection, 1980s-1990s and undated RL.00863
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Original Videotapes, 1980s-1990s, 49 boxes
  - 106. 20 Best, v. 9. 1986. Umatic. TRT: Unknown. (Box 8)
    - L'Oreal: Eyes (Box 8)
    - Eggs: Woodhouse (Box 8)
    - Opel Corsa: Graduette (Box 8)
    - American Express: If Only… (Box 8)
    - Levi's: Gym (Box 8)
    - Sprite: Re-Launch (Box 8)
    - IMEC: Bras (Box 8)
    - Bausch & Lomb: Soft Lens (Box 8)
    - Chevette (Box 8)
    - Nescafé: Story of Coffee (Box 8)
    - Esso: Catseyes (Box 8)
    - Alka Seltzer: Board Room (Box 8)
    - Coca-Cola: Lost and Found Love (Box 8)
    - Outline: Body (Box 8)
    - Glad: Rubbish Bag (Box 8)
    - Martini Bianco: Bottle (Box 8)
    - Goodyear: Rallye (Box 8)
    - Mortein (fly spray): Homestead (Box 8)
    - Kodak: Pop Up No. 2 (Box 8)
    - Martini Rosso: Roller Waitress (Box 8)
    - Coca-Cola: Teach the World (Box 8)
  - 107. The 20th All Japan Radio & TV Commercial Council (ACC) Film Festival, ACC Award 1-1, no. 3 of 4. Undated. Umatic. TRT: Unknown.
    - Suntory/Suntory Red: Reiko Ohara (Box 8)
    - Olympus/Camera: Kumiko Oba (Box 8)
    - Kirin Breweries/Lager Beer: Summer Festival (Box 8)
    - Suntory/Suntory Old: Alaska (Box 8)
    - Coca-Cola/Coke: Come on in; Coke '80; Balloon (Box 8)
    - Nissin Oil Mills/Salad Oil (Box 8)
    - Kanebo/Lady '80 Lipstick: Spring campaign (Box 8)
    - Shiseido/Bravas Hair Liquid: Down East (Box 8)
    - Shiseido/Basubon Soap: Seiji Miyaguchi (Box 8)
    - Shiseido/Cosmetics (Box 8)
    - Lion Fat & Oil Co./Mama Lemon: Wakkanai (Box 8)
    - Matsushita Electric Industrial/Bath Buzard (Box 8)
    - Matsushita Electric Industrial/Electric Bulb (Box 8)
    - Semedain/Semedain Glue 3000: Everlasting (Box 8)
    - Matsushita Electric/Refrigerator: Orphaned Seal (Box 8)
    - Renown/Durban: A Woman's Dream (Box 8)
    - Matsushita Electric/Multiplex Pana Colour (Box 8)
    - Matsushita Electric/Technics: Forgotten Sound (Box 8)
    - Matsushita Electric/Multiplex Quintrix 7000 (Box 8)
    - Yamaha/Towny: On the Street (Box 8)
    - Toyota/Carina: Alps (Box 8)
    - Yamaha/Towny: On the Street (Box 8)
    - Nissan/Pulser: City (Box 8)
    - Fuji Film/Fuji Colour Print: Summer (Box 8)
    - Minolta Camera/Minolta x-7: Yoshiko in Bathing Suit (Box 8)
    - Marui/Personal Present Campaign: Tennis (Box 8)
    - All Nippon Airways/Sky Holiday in Okinawa (Box 8)
    - Tokyu Department Store/Toyoko Noren Gai: Lots of Goodies (Box 8)
    - Shogakukan/Encyclopedia (Box 8)
    - Toyota/Corporate: From the Country of Oil (Box 8)
    - Public Advertising Corp.: Waterworks (Box 8)
    - Suntory/Suntory Royal: Kirimanjaro (Box 8)
    - Toyota/Corporate: Blizzard (Box 8)
    - Nikka Breweries/Super Nikka: Keirian (China); Everyday Life; Rooftop (Box 8)
    - Matsushita Electric/Separate 77: TV Sound Has Begun to Move (Box 8)
    - Ajinomoto/Mayonnaise: Cucumbers; Lettuce; Celery (Box 8)
    - Okura Shuzo/Gekkeikan (Sake): Food (Box 8)
  - 108. World Wide Creative Awards, Print. Undated. Umatic. TRT: Unknown. (Box 8)
  - 109. McCann Worldwide Awards 1985, Regional Winner Reel. 1985. Umatic. TRT: 32:00
    - Infoods: Friend Chips (Box 8)
    - Johnson: Bio-Spray (Box 8)
    - Arabia: Finn Crystal (Box 8)
    - Serla: Paper Towels (Box 8)
    - Hanames: Faucets (Box 8)
    - Viking Line: Lighthouse Keeper (Box 8)
    - Esso: Forecourt (Box 8)
    - Eiser: Pantyhose (Box 8)
    - Heksavit (Box 8)
    - Helsingin Puhelinyhdistys: Kokikkaasti; Kaikessa Rauhassa; Modernisti (Box 8)
    - McCann Finland: Riskit Kuriin (Box 8)
    - Kodak (Box 8)
    - Eiser (Box 8)
    - Opel: Kadett; Senator (Box 8)
    - Lepoun: Milda (Box 8)
    - Vaasan (Box 8)
    - Zwan: Muppets (Box 8)
    - Bimbo: Panque (Box 8)
    - Nescafé Coffee: Diplomat Cita (Box 8)
    - Goodyear: Performance (Box 8)
    - Nestlé Quik: Nave Especial/Nino (Box 8)
    - GM Eurosport: Reflejos (Box 8)
    - GM Eurosport: Banderas (Box 8)
    - GM Pickups C-15/20: Tren (Box 8)
    - GM: Anniversary (Box 8)
    - Camino Real Hotel (Box 8)
    - Goodyear Tires: Eagle GT (Box 8)
    - General Motors: 50th anniversary launch (Box 8)
    - California Milk Advisory Board: Pole Vaulter (Box 8)
    - Del Monte: Work Hard (Box 8)
    - Wells Fargo: Columbia (Box 8)
    - Ortho: High Tech (Box 8)
    - Del Monte: Racquetball (Box 8)
    - National Dairy Board: Ballet (Box 8)
    - National Dairy Board: School (Box 8)
    - National Dairy Board: Calcium campaign (Box 8)
    - California Milk Board: Fluid Milk campaign (Box 8)
    - Wells Fargo: Auto Loan campaign (Box 8)
    - PGandE: Corporate Image campaign (Box 8)
    - Del Monte Lite Canned Fruit: Come On Over campaign (Box 8)
    - Del Monte Fruit Snacks: Magazine campaign (Box 8)
    - Chevron Chemical: Can 17 (Box 8)
    - Community Chest: Mime (Box 8)
    - Ole Square: Crisps (Box 8)
    - Johnson & Johnson: Baby Powder (Box 8)
    - Del Monte: Tomato Catsup (Box 8)
    - Ese Thomson: Technology (Box 8)
    - Tiger Beer (Box 8)
    - Levi's (Box 8)
    - Anchor Beer (Box 8)
    - Stand Up for Singapore (Box 8)
    - Kodak (Box 8)
    - Coke/McDonald's tie-in (Box 8)
    - Papermate: Executive Collection (Box 8)
    - Daikin Skyair Air Conditioner (Box 8)
    - Tiger Beer: Strikes Gold Again (Box 8)
    - Cherry Shoe Polish (Box 8)
  - 110. Global Advertising: The Facts and Fantasy. 1986. Umatic. TRT: Unknown.
    - Coca-Cola: Hillside (Box 8)
    - Coca-Cola International: Olympic Journey; Stopover; Diner; On the Beach; Sizzle (Box 8)
    - Camel: Tent Raft (Box 8)
    - Marlboro Montage (Box 8)
    - Cinzano (Box 8)
    - Martini Rosso Montage (Box 8)
    - Esso Montage: Tiger (Box 8)
    - Unilever Montage: Housewife interview (Box 8)
    - Nescafé Montage (Box 8)
    - Summary Montage (Box 8)
  - 111. Barry Day On Tape, Global Advertising: The Facts and the Fantasy. 1986. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    [Discussion about the prospect of global brands: find a global need; come up with a brand; then maybe you can have a global brand. Your product has to be used the same everywhere. Coke is used as the prime example. Analysis of cost, production, psychology. Global advertising has to be basic but not boring. Imagery crosses cultural boundaries. Cinzano's failure in the global market vs. Martini's success. Differences between global marketing and global brands.]
    - Coke: Hilltop (Box 8)
    - Coke is It (Brazil) (Box 8)
    - Coke is It (Spanish) (Box 8)
    - Coke is It (Japan) (Box 8)
    - Coke is It (English) (Box 8)
    - Camel: River Raft (Box 8)
    - Camel Montage (Box 8)
    - Marlboro: Marlboro Country (Box 8)
    - Marlboro Montage (Box 8)
    - Cinzano (Box 8)
    - Martini (Box 8)
    - Esso Montage (Box 8)
    - Stork Margarine Montage (Box 8)
    - Nescafé (Box 8)
  - 112. Global Advertising: The Facts and Fantasy. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - Coke: Hilltop (Box 8)
    - Coke is It (Brazil) (Box 8)
    - Coke is It (Spanish) (Box 8)
    - Coke is It (Japan) (Box 8)
    - Coke is It (English) (Box 8)
    - Camel: River Raft (Box 8)
    - Camel Montage (Box 8)
    - Marlboro: Marlboro Country (Box 8)
    - Marlboro Montage (Box 8)
    - Cinzano (Box 8)
    - Martini (Box 8)
    - Esso Montage (Box 8)
    - Stork Margarine Montage (Box 8)
    - Nescafé (Box 8)
  - 113. Beijing 87 Global Advertising: The Facts and Fantasy, Part 2. 1987. Umatic. TRT: Unknown. (Box 8)
  - 114. Beijing 87 Global Advertising: The Facts and Fantasy, Part 1. 1987. Umatic. TRT: Unknown. (Box 8)
  - 115. Global Advertising: The Facts and Fantasy. 1986. Umatic. PAL. TRT: Unknown.
    - Coca-Cola: Hillside (Box 8)
    - Coca-Cola International: Olympic Journey; Stopover; Diner; On the Beach; Sizzle (Box 8)
    - Camel: Tent Raft (Box 8)
    - Marlboro Montage (Box 8)
    - Cinzano (Box 8)
    - Martini Rosso Montage (Box 8)
    - Esso Montage: Tiger (Box 8)
    - Unilever Montage: Housewife interview (Box 8)
    - Nescafé Montage (Box 8)
    - Summary Montage (Box 8)
  - 116. Global Edit With Montage. 1984. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 4:20
    - Coca-Cola (Box 8)
    - L'Oreal (Box 8)
    - Kodak (Box 8)
    - Esso (Box 8)
    - Nabisco (Box 8)
    - Opel (Box 8)
    - Del Monte (Box 8)
    - Philips (Box 8)
    - Texas Instruments (Box 8)
    - Camel (Box 8)
    - Goodyear (Box 8)
    - Gillette (Box 8)
    - Papermate (Box 8)
    - Unilever (Box 8)
    - Nescafé (Box 8)
    - Levi's (Box 8)
    - Martini (Box 8)
  - 117. International Air Check, v. 2, no. 4. 1980. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - Coca-Cola: Teach the World (Box 8)
    - Kellogg's Cereals: Christmas Tree (Box 8)
    - McDonald's: Morning (Box 8)
    - Kodak Colorburst: Ms. Foster (Box 8)
    - Bell System: Reach Out (Box 8)
    - Craigs Traveller's Checks (Box 8)
    - Heinz Salad: Salad Days (Box 8)
    - Sharpe's Extra Strong Mints: Socks (Box 8)
    - Cadbury's Smash: Robots (Box 8)
    - Supersoft Hair Spray: Tom & Betty (Box 8)
    - Pepsi Cola: Summertime Blues (Box 8)
    - Colt 45 Malt Liquor: Lucky Lady (Box 8)
    - Levi-Strauss: Round Up (Box 8)
    - TDK Audio Cassettes: Music Machine (Box 8)
    - Canon P10-D Calculator: Best Seller (Box 8)
    - Heineken: Cricket (Box 8)
    - Martini Rose: Tap Dance (Box 8)
    - Kinney Shoes: Straw Hat (Box 8)
    - Dr. Pepper: School Review (Box 8)
    - Red Rose Tea: Trio (Box 8)
    - Continental Airlines: Disco (Box 8)
    - Purina Ocean Blend Cat Food: Chow-Chow-Chow (Box 8)
    - Woodpecker Cider: Hereford Lightning (Box 8)
    - Kellogg's Rice Krispies: Breakfast for You (Box 8)
    - Aunt Jemima Waffles: I'm a…I'm a… (Box 8)
    - Pizza Hut: Taco Tasting (Box 8)
    - Doublemint Gum: Double Dribble (Box 8)
    - Budweiser Beer: Workers (Box 8)
    - GTE Flip Phone: Bedroom Song (Box 8)
    - Boraxo Hand Cleaner: Shake Hands (Box 8)
    - Peter Paul Candies: Feel Like a Nut (Box 8)
    - Fiat Strada (U.K.): Figaro (Box 8)
    - Eggs (U.K.): Crack a Good Meal (Box 8)
    - Kit Kat Candy (Switzerland): Couple (Box 8)
    - Coca-Cola (Spain): Coke Adds Life (Box 8)
    - Wrigley's Gum (France): I Feel Love (Box 8)
    - Geramont Cheese (France): Creamy Smooth (Box 8)
    - Chanel #5 Perfume: Blue Sky (Box 8)
    - Toyota Trucks (Australia): Best Pick-Up (Box 8)
    - Jockey Hip Briefs (Australia): Puttin' Us On (Box 8)
    - Burlington Sheets: Dracula (Box 8)
    - Baranne Shoe Crème (France): I Use a Cream (Box 8)
    - Health Education Council: Look After Yourself (Box 8)
    - Terry Jelly Orange: Kids As Adults (Box 8)
    - Heath Candy: Michaelangelo (Box 8)
    - Rowntree Violet Crumble: Australia's Crumbling (Box 8)
    - Batna Caramel (France): Professeur (Box 8)
    - Wrigley's Spearmint Gum: Glider (Box 8)
    - Life Saver Bubble Yum (Switzerland): Spotlight (Box 8)
    - Kraft Caramel: Pocket Full (Box 8)
    - Lay's Potato Chips: School Bus (Box 8)
    - Smith Square Crisp (U.K.): Workmen (Box 8)
    - Heinz Spaghetti (U.K.): Mmmm (Box 8)
    - Oodles of Noodles Soup: Corey (Box 8)
    - Prize Yoghurt (U.K.): Pied Piper (Box 8)
    - Cook Electric (U.K.): Hey Good Lookin' (Box 8)
    - Natural Gas (Australia): Living Flame (Box 8)
    - Mobil 1 Motor Oil: Fried Egg (Box 8)
    - Exxon Uniflo Oil: 200 Million Gallons (Box 8)
    - Texaco: Tomato and Egg (Box 8)
    - Owens Corning Insulation: Pink Glow (Box 8)
    - Whirlpool: Autumn (Box 8)
    - T.I. Corporation: Awards (Box 8)
    - Ford: Incredible Tour (Box 8)
    - Chrysler: Rebate (Box 8)
    - IBM Office Systems: This Fast? (Box 8)
    - General Electric: Daughter's Dance (Box 8)
    - Kriter Wine (U.K.): Pop (Box 8)
    - Carling Beer (U.K.): Steam Cabinet (Box 8)
    - Federal Express: Paper Explosion (Box 8)
    - Schliltz Light Beer: George Burns (Box 8)
    - Maxim Coffee: Coffee Cantata (Box 8)
    - American Tourister Luggage: Dummy (Box 8)
    - Qantas Airlines: Day Flight (Box 8)
    - C&C Cola: Lovely Home (Box 8)
    - Polaroid One-Step: Hot Dog (Box 8)
    - Fortunoff's: Bacall/Source (Box 8)
    - Fidelity Chess Challenger: Space (Box 8)
    - Lakeside Computer Protection: Dome Heads (Box 8)
    - Code Name Sector (Parker Brothers): Computer Brain (Box 8)
    - Mego Mini-Vid: Jail (Box 8)
    - Einstein (Caastle Toys): Johnson (Box 8)
    - Manial by Ideal: Lightning (Box 8)
    - Scrabble Sensor (Selchow & Richter): World's First (Box 8)
    - Alphi (Playskool): Once in a While (Box 8)
    - Brittania Sportswear: Rome (Box 8)
    - Bon Jour Jeans: Sports Car (Box 8)
    - Jou Jou Jeans: Lips (Box 8)
    - Jordache Jeans: Horse (Box 8)
    - Jordache Bag Jeans: Get Into It (Box 8)
    - Kasper Jeans: Beautiful Dreams (Box 8)
    - Jean Elle by Glenora: Paris (Box 8)
    - Levi Women's Wear: Neon Woman (Box 8)
    - Levi's Work Jeans: Welder (Box 8)
    - Sasson Jeans: Rangers (Box 8)
    - Sasson Stretch: Tampoline (Box 8)
    - Stephen Burrows Jeans: Model (Box 8)
    - Studio 54 Jeans; Everyone Can Get in (Box 8)
    - Wrangler: London (Box 8)
    - Wrangler: Paris (Box 8)
    - Selsun Blue Shampoo: Globe (Box 8)
    - VO-5 Shampoo (U.K.): Flat to Fluffy (Box 8)
    - Prell Concentrate: Flat to Fluffy (Box 8)
    - Balm Barr Lotion: Model (Box 8)
    - Wondra Lotion: Captain (Box 8)
    - Oil of Olay: Not 21 (Box 8)
    - Nivea Cream: Baby Skin (Box 8)
    - Dial Soap: New Morning (Box 8)
    - Gleem Toothpaste: Mirror Dialogue (Box 8)
    - Aqua-Fresh Toothpaste: But Mother! (Box 8)
    - Crest Toothpaste: Toothopolis (Box 8)
    - Aqua-Fresh Toothpaste (U.K.): Crunch (Box 8)
    - Dentyne Gum: Star (Box 8)
    - Gillette Foamy Shave Cream: Hiker (Box 8)
  - 118. International Air Check, v. 4, no. 1. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 8)
  - 119. International Brand Management, Instanbul Conference. 1984. Umatic. TRT: Unknown. (Box 8)
  - 120. International Film Festival--Cannes 1986, Commercials Entered by McCann-DeVilliers. 1986. Umatic. PAL. TRT: Unknown. (Box 8)
  - 121. Perspectives on Global Creativity: Agency Viewpoints 9A. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 9)
    [Balancing the dream of reaching the world with a single message; the practical realities of global advertising; Adweek conference on global creativity; Barry Day leads discussion with top agency executives.]
  - 122. World of Difference Without Barry. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 9)
  - 123. A World of Difference, Version 11. 1984. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - Gordon's Vodka (Puerto Rico) (Box 9)
    - Vidal: White Horse (Italy) (Box 9)
    - L'Oreal: Hair Scapes (Box 9)
    - Immec: Bras (Box 9)
    - Ad Colour: Sports Shoes (Hong Kong) (Box 9)
    - Patriaca Chairs: Western Saloon (Italy) (Box 9)
    - Glad: Trash Bags (Belgium) (Box 9)
    - Outline: Zip (U.K.) (Box 9)
    - Bausch & Lomb: Soft Lens (Australia) (Box 9)
    - Christie's: Soft Cookies (Canada) (Box 9)
    - Opel Corsa: Thimble (France) (Box 9)
    - D.B. Railways: Snow (Germany) (Box 9)
    - GM Trucks: Mexico (Brazil) (Box 9)
    - Eggs: Woodhouse (U.K.) (Box 9)
    - Opel Corsa: The Graduate (Italy) (Box 9)
    - Esso: Cat's Eyes (U.K.) (Box 9)
    - L'Oreal: Nail Polish (Box 9)
    - Kodak: Pop Up Book (U.K.) (Box 9)
    - Levi's: Desert (Germany) (Box 9)
    - Coca-Cola: Soccermania (Box 9)
    - Martini: Disco (U.K.) (Box 9)
    - Telephone: Holiday Romance (Italy) (Box 9)
    - Mortein: Mozzies (Australia) (Box 9)
    - Martini Rosso: Skating Waitress (U.K.) (Box 9)
    - Martini Bianco: Bottle (U.K.) (Box 9)
  - 124. Domestos Guidelines. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    [Goal is to provide guidance for Domestos as it begins to move into other countries from its origins in the U.K. Domestos is a product which promises protection of the family's health from germs. Study/analysis of how Domestos went about expanding into other markets by studying those markets and understanding them.]
    - Germany (Box 9)
    - Italy (Box 9)
    - Finland (Box 9)
    - Australia (Box 9)
    - Canada (Box 9)
    - Japan (Box 9)
    - South Africa (Box 9)
    - France (Box 9)
    - France (Box 9)
    - Switzerland (Box 9)
    - U.K. (Box 9)
  - 125. Perspectives on Global Creativity: The Director's Touch 9C. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 9)
    [Roundtable discussion by directors of commercials on how the director constributes to global creativity and advertising; how humor can be used to cross cultural boundaries.]
  - 126. Humour in Advertising. 1986. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - Kronenberg: Canaletto (Box 9)
    - Lee Cooper: Directed by Jean Paul Goude (Box 9)
    - Philips: Bolero (Box 9)
    - Heineken: B-Movie (Box 9)
    - Dulux: Gallery (Roger Woodburn) (Box 9)
    - Cockburns: Rescue (Box 9)
    - Holstein Pils: Stanwyck (Box 9)
    - Castlemaine XXXX: Flying Doctor (John Marles) (Box 9)
    - Fosters: Ballet (Bob Brooks) (Box 9)
    - John Smith: Dog (Box 9)
    - John Smith: True Love (Box 9)
    - John Smith: Wrong Crowd (Peter Webb) (Box 9)
    - John Smith: Song and Dance (Peter Webb) (Box 9)
    - Kellogg's: Pack Shot (Box 9)
    - Maxwell House: Picnic (Box 9)
    - Sunday Times: Royal Family (Box 9)
    - Sunday Times: Michael Parkinson (Box 9)
    - Royal Dutch Cigars: Car (Paul Weiland) (Box 9)
    - Sunday Times: Bernard Levin (Box 9)
    - Sunday Times: Private Patient (Box 9)
    - Sunday Times: British Way of Love (Box 9)
    - British Telecom: Custer (Paul Weiland) (Box 9)
    - Nat West: Doddle (Paul Weiland) (Box 9)
    - Silvikrin: Mopheads (Roger Lunn) (Box 9)
    - Smith's Square Crisps: Room (Roger Woodburn) (Box 9)
    - Eggs: Nut (Roger Woodburn) (Box 9)
    - Heineken: Snowman (Roger Woodburn) (Box 9)
    - Trebor Extra Strong Mints: Balloon (Box 9)
    - Walkers Fries: Can't Decide (Box 9)
    - Mumm Champagne: Launch (Box 9)
    - Carling Black Label: Snooker (Terry Lovelock) (Box 9)
    - Cresta: Chantilly Lace (Richard Purdum) (Box 9)
    - Olympus: The Pits (Bob Brooks) (Box 9)
    - Leeds Liquid Gold: Bird's Nest (Box 9)
    - Hellman's: Clarence (Len Fulford) (Box 9)
    - Smash: St. Martinas (Len Fulford) (Box 9)
    - Hofmeister: Sportsman (Box 9)
  - 127. Humour in Advertising. 1986. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - Corning: In Laws (Lee Lacy) (Box 9)
    - Jello: Spoon (Jim Johnston) (Box 9)
    - Hellman's: Potato Salad (John Danza) (Box 9)
    - Robitussin: Sick Mom (Paul Guliner) (Box 9)
    - Midas: Hi Mom (Paul Guliner) (Box 9)
    - Breakstone: Bedtime (Dick Loew) (Box 9)
    - Del Monte: Lasagna (Stew Birbrower) (Box 9)
    - Clorox: White Christmas (Robert Lieberman) (Box 9)
    - Lotto: Debutantes (Michael McNamara) (Box 9)
    - McDonald's: She Likes Me (Jim McGorman) (Box 9)
    - Live at Five: Guy Atchley (Jim McGorman) (Box 9)
    - Alpo: Smile (Jim McGorman) (Box 9)
    - Wallach's: We Fit You (Box 9)
  - 128. Humour in Advertising. 1977. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 9)
    [Barry Day commentary on humor in advertising. Unsuccessful attempts; movie/TV/musical stars--familiarity breeds instant comedy; parody of familiar movie/TV formats; nostalgia; using stereotypes (especially of foreigners) to generate humor; humor is based in reality--but exaggeration allows us to laugh at ourselves; simplified slice of life allows us to remain separate.]
  - 129. Humour in Advertising. 1986. Umatic. PAL. TRT: 4:44 (Box 9)
  - 130. Subaru--Love/Hate (Humour in Advertising). Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 9)
  - 131. Material That Would Be Good for Humour. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - Hertz: Vultures (Box 9)
    - Samsonite: Building Falls (Box 9)
    - Waterman Pens: Little Girl (Box 9)
    - BASF: Lassie (Box 9)
    - Pioneer: Boogie Man (Box 9)
    - Hippopotomus Restaurant: Woody Allen (Box 9)
    - Italian Ceramic Tile (Box 9)
  - 132. The Ad Council and the Reagans. 1986. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - Ad Council Conference: Anti-Drug Program (Box 9)
    - Ronald Reagan: Award Presentation and Acceptance Speech (Box 9)
    - Cocaine: The Big Lie PSA featuring Nancy Reagan (Box 9)
  - 133. Advertising Council, Cassette #8, July-December 1985 Mailing. 1985. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - Drunk Driving (Box 9)
    - National Guard and Reserve (Box 9)
    - Disabled Persons (Box 9)
    - American Red Cross: Health Campaign (Box 9)
    - Statue of Liberty: Ellis Island Centennial (Box 9)
    - Religion in American Life (Box 9)
    - Forest Fire Prevention (Box 9)
    - National Alliance of Business: Service Station (Box 9)
    - National Alliance of Business: Hiring Hall (Box 9)
    - American Red Cross: Corporate Campaign (Box 9)
    - Drug Abuse Prevention (Box 9)
    - Direct Deposit Campaign (Box 9)
  - 134. Ad Council, US Treasury, Direct Deposit. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 9)
  - 135. Japan: Bridges and Barriers (Americans in Japan). Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 9)
    [27-minute program about the contact and influences between Japan and the U.S.]
  - 136. The Company Behind the Brand. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 18:00 (Box 10)
    [Chuck Mittelstadt (Manager, Center for Advertising Studies--CAS) discussing the invisible company behind all the brands we see and associate with. The company is becoming a more visible element. The program discusses the new accent on the company in the U.S.]
  - 137. A.A.A.A. Conference at Helmsley Hotel; Does the Size of Mega-Agencies Enhance or Inhibit Creativity?. 1987. Umatic. TRT: 52:00
    - Ad Council: Prevent Forest Fires (Box 10)
    - California Raisins (Box 10)
  - 138. Corporate Advertising, Part II. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: 10:00
    - Boeing (Box 10)
    - Boeing (Box 10)
    - Timken Special Alloy Steel (Box 10)
  - 139. W.R. Grace & Company, Deficit Trial. 1986. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 10)
    [One step ahead of a changing world. Futuristic courtroom trial of man who did nothing about the federal deficit in 1986.]
  - 140. Excess in Advertising. 1984. Umatic. PAL. TRT: Unknown. (Box 10)
  - 141. The Explosion of In-Store Advertising. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 25:00 (Box 10)
  - [142: Missing] (Box 10)
  - [143: Missing] (Box 10)
  - [144: Missing] (Box 10)
  - 145. Point-of-Purchase Video. Undated. Umatic. TRT: 32:00 (Box 10)
    [Video as part of the in-store display; using the store itself for image advertising.]
  - 146. Print Renaissance. Undated. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 10)
  - 147. Southbank Show, Making a Commercial. Undated. Umatic. TRT: Unknown. (Box 10)
  - 148. Table Talk A Preview of Nestlé Culinary Do's and Don'ts Tape. 1986. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown. (Box 10)
  - 149. What Advertising Is Today, v. 1. Undated. VHSSecam. TRT: Unknown. (Box 10)
  - 150. What Advertising Is Today, v. 2. Undated. VHSSecam. TRT: Unknown. (Box 10)
  - 151. Corporate Advertising, Part I. 1978. Umatic. NTSC. TRT: Unknown.
    - G.E.: Edison/Outdoor Lighting (Box 10)
    - Levi Jeans: Brand Name (Box 10)
    - IBM: Rodriques Family (Box 10)
    - St. Regis: Tap Dancer (Box 10)
    - Georgia Pacific: Log Cabin (Box 10)
    - IBM: Newspaper (Box 10)
    - Georgia Pacific: Barn Raising (Box 10)
    - Weyerhauser: Elio Gauditz (Box 10)
    - Natural Gas: Apple Pie (Box 10)
    - Atlantic Richfield: Aging (Box 10)
    - Sony: Agent (Box 10)
    - Atlantic Richfield: Land Management (Box 10)
    - Xerox: Billingsly (Box 10)
    - Atlantic Richfield: Conservation (Box 10)
    - Xerox: Playground (Box 10)
    - International T&T/Water Pumps: Flygt (Box 10)
    - Gulf: Explosives (Box 10)
    - Xerox: Money (Box 10)
    - Georgia Pacific: Ticker Tape (Box 10)
    - G.E.: Edison/Refrigerators (Box 10)
    - Western Electric: Blue Danube (Box 10)
    - Texaco: Opera--Wyoming (Box 10)
    - Miller High Life: Xmas (Box 10)
    - United Technologies: The Little Things (Box 10)
    - IBM: Supermarket (Box 10)
    - Fultz, Lacasse & Associates: Dubuque (Box 10)
    - Georgia Pacific: Ghost Town (Box 10)
    - TRW: Growing Plains (Box 10)